

# Matt Ayers.

I'm trained as an product designer, and since 2006 have been using the methods of design to create new services for companies to give them advantage in the marketplace. I have worked in a diverse range of industries across New Zealand from media and manufacturing, to power and financial services.

**Work Experience** 

## **Experience Designer**

DNA Design

Mar 2015 - Present

Auckland, NZ

Working on innovation, design and business improvement projects spanning product, service, channel, process, environment and engagement.

## **Head of Design**

Sustainable Business Network

May 2013 - Feb 2015

Auckland, NZ

The Head of Design role works with the development of services across the SBN, increasing cohesion among the various services offered, and the development of design capacity in the SBN staff.

#### Founder

The Studio

2011 - May 2013

Auckland, NZ

A one day event for emerging leaders to explore how alternative disciplines like design & game mechanics can fundumentally change organisations.

- Established the first event (23 leaders, 5 experienced speakers from NZ & Australia).
- Established a small organising team for future studio events.

### Founder

Sandbox NZ

2010 - Nov 2012

Auckland, NZ

Established a boutique advisory service for projects in Design & Strategy:

- Advised in the development of a partnership strategy for a Auckland mentoring charity called Brothers in Arms.
- Facilitated a strategy day to build collaboration in the performance improvement teams of Middlemore Hospital.
- Facilitated Business Model workshops for Polson Higgs in cities around NZ.

### **Business Catalyst**

Polson Higgs

Jan 2006 - Jul 2010

Dunedin, NZ

Medium sized chartered accountant firm based in Dunedin, New Zealand.

- Established a new innovation service line for the firm using Design Methods.
- Built a team with expertise in anthropology, engineering, design, & architecture.
- Completed a range of projects in product & service development in industries including manufacturing, tourism & mass media.

## Education

#### **University of Otago**

BAppSci, Design for Technology 2002-2005

#### Reference

# Steve Maskill

Design Director / Principal, DNA Design Stephen.Maskell@dna.co.nz, 021 565 606